Mao, you have a family?
マオは家族がいるんだ
I'm the only one in this unit
who has a family of his own.
この部隊で家族持ちは私だけだよ
私の所属は砲兵部隊だ
I belonged on the artillery unit.
人の頭が入るような太さの大砲をポンポン撃ってた
I shot off guns so big you
could stick your head inside.
When I was drifting around,
Koko just so happened to be in Asia.
路頭に迷っていた時
偶然アジアを訪れていたココさんが私を雇ってくれた
She was kind enough to hire me.
As you can see in the info before you...
ええ　お手元の資料にありますとおり
...it's an air delivery!
空輸です
Thank you so much, Miss Hekmatyar.
ありがとうございます
ミス·ヘクマティアル
We appreciate your transporting us.
我々の輸送を　よろしくお願いします
Dragan Nikolaevich is the leader of
the militia group, the Balkan Dragons,
「ドラガン·ニコラヴィッチ」は民兵組織「バルカン·ドラゴン」
通称「バルドラ」のリーダー
also known as Baldra.
I just said you've got ten frigging doctors
canned up in that transport plane!
テメエあの輸送機ん中に
クソ医者を十人ばがし詰め込んでんだろっつってんだよ
Pop the hatch and toss them out!
フタ開けてひり出せ
もう　増えちゃった
Gosh darn it! They're multiplying!
We're getting more guys in black berets.
増えちゃったよ　黒帽子
Our presence here is causing
problems for Miss Hekmatyar.
私たちの存在がミス·ヘクマティアルの迷惑に
荷物のフリをしているわけにはいかない
I cannot sit and pretend I'm cargo.
You're a doctor who treats the people I shoot.
俺が撃った敵を治す医者
That makes you an enemy, too.
だったらお前も敵じゃん
ココ　どうするね
Koko, whadda you want us to do?
We've only got one option
now that it's come to this.
もうこうなっちゃ仕方ないでしょう
Annihilate the Balkan Dragons militia group!
民兵「バルカン·ドラゴン」を撃滅せよ
近っ
Close! Close!
Th-There's a gunfight?!
銃撃戦？
We have always stood on the borderland.
我們始終踱步於境界線之上
I'm enjoying the view from here.
皆因此境風景獨好
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe...
Eeny,meeny,miny,moe...
一，二，三，四...
much the same
其實都一樣
We have always stood on the borderland.
我們始終踱步於境界線之上
日聽   貓日和
框框
I'm enjoying the view from here.
皆因此境風景獨好
翻譯  TL舊民
時軸  ZZZ
後期   aoi
神
島
魔
惡
&
諸
Pike or shield?
Pike or shield?  負けたくはない　でも傷つけたくもない
矛 or 盾？ 不想認輸 可是又不願受傷害
Maketaku wa nai demo kizu tsuketaku mo nai
Te ni totte tashikameteta
手に取って　確かめてた
先挑一樣在手中仔細掂量
Kitto modorenain datte
きっと戻れないんだって
可是發現再要反悔為時已晚
Whose side are you on?
你選的是哪邊？
(Don't want to know!) Omoide wa kase
Don't want to know!  思い出は枷
Don't want to know!  思念是枷鎖
(Don't want to know!) Atozuke no love
Don't want to know!  後付けのlove
Don't want to know!  追悔莫及的愛
(Don't want to know!) Yasashisa wa ada
Don't want to know!  優しさは仇
Don't want to know!  溫柔是弱點
We have always stood on the borderland.
我們始終踱步於境界線之上
広げる両手　keep balance
張開雙臂保持平衡
Hirogeru ryoute keep balance
Yori takaku toberu hou he
より高く飛べる方へ
向著更高的天空振臂而飛
Mamoritai yo
守りたいよ 僕らの翼のないこの背中に背負った
唯獨想保護的是.. 背負於我們那折翼的背膀之上的
Bokura no tsubasa no nai kono senaka ni seotta
Reality & Dream
真實 & 夢想
Reality and Dream
Reality & Dream
真實 & 夢想
Reality and Dream
Reality & Dream
真實 & 夢想
Stay back! My subordinates
are not to come outside!
来るな　俺の部下は絶対出て来るな
ミス·ヘクマティアル　お願いだ
Miss Hekmatyar, please!
Please make them stop!
止めてください
Stupid weapons dealer!
武器商人
Don't fire, Jonah!
撃つな　ヨナ
Don't shoot.
撃つな
Dammit! Damn it!
ッキショう　あのアマ
Damn that bitch!
Unforgivable!
I'll never forgive the hound!
許さね　許さね
いつでぶっ殺してやる
I'll kill her sooner or later!
Clear!
クリア
--Clear!
Clear!
クリア
What's our damage?
こちらのダメージ
Zero.
ゼロ
Dragon Shooter phase.2
I can't believe you did that on my airfield!
私の空港でなんってことを
Miss Hekmatyar, you've made
a mountain of Baldra corpses!
ミス·ヘクマティアル
「バルドラ」の死体の山を築き上げて
If their boss had behaved
in a gentlemanly manner,
彼らのボスが紳士的であれば
I believe we could have
taken a different path, Captain.
これ以外の道はあったと思います　大尉
The problem is: How are we
going to leave this country? Right?
問題はどうやてこの国から出るか　だろう
They're going to attack once we're in the air.
絶対空中で攻撃される
Could we go by land?
陸路？
And bring our "cargo" with us? Impossible.
品物を連れて
無理だ
That Baldra guy drove
off with the chief doctor.
「バルドラ」って奴が医師長を車で連れ去った
This wouldn't have happened
if I shot him back there.
あの時打てばこんな事には
Why didn't you let me shoot him?
何で撃たせなかったんだ
Jonah, that scumbag isn't
worthy of dying by your hands.
ヨナ
あんな奴は君が撃つほどの人間ではない
The sharpness of a knight's sword
changes based off of what it kills.
騎士の剣は何を斬ったかにより斬れ味を変える
I could never let you become
a worthless, dull blade.
君がどうしよもない鈍らになるのを私は許さん
Koko, that had too many
metaphors for me to understand.
ココの話は例えが多くてよく分からない
You'll understand soon enough.
すぐ分かるようになる
Plus I somewhat intentionally let him get away.
それと　奴を逃したのはちょっとわざとでもあるんだよ
Are you even giving this serious thought?!
真面目に考えてんのかよおめーはよ
What?! And what about you, Lutz?
何だと　ルツこそなんだよ
The idea that we'd nab a tank is stupid!
戦車バクルって　バカか
Now, now! Offer suggestions
before you start arguing.
はいはい
喧嘩する前に案を出す
But this is a pretty sticky situation.
と言っても状況はかなり厳しい
If we don't hurry, that old fart is
going to come back with an army!
急がないと　あのおっさんが大勢連れて戻って来る
What kind of anti-aerial
weaponry do they have?
敵の対空装備は
Rocket launchers and anti-aircraft guns.
ロケットランチャーに対空砲
There is also a possibility that
they will launch missiles at us.
ミサイルを撃って来る可能性もある
They definitely will.
絶対撃つ
What if we use flares?
フレアを使えば
Don't make it sound so easy.
簡単に言うなよ
What would we do after we shot them?
その後どうする
We could use one of those 122mm guns...
あの122ミリ砲で
Mao, repeat that!
マオ　もう一度
Like I said, let's use a 122mm gun
to destroy their missile launch pad.
ですから　122ミリ砲でミサイル発射台を潰しましょう
Okay! Let's go with that.
OK　それで行こう
I know this is sudden, Captain, but could
you sell one of your 122mm guns to us?
突然ですが大尉
122ミリ砲を一門お譲りくださいませんか
For a reasonable price, of course.
勿論適正価格で
We'll be gone within the next ten minutes.
我々は後10分でこの場から去ります
お聞きくだされば
If you do as we ask, we'll give you
a 20% discount on your entire next order.
次回全商品二割引でご提供させて
もう　好きにしてください
Do whatever you want.
Ugo, you and the pilot
go prepare for take off.
ウゴ　機長と共に離陸準備
了解
Roger!
Everyone else, follow Mao's instructions
他の者はマオの指示に従って
and help him load a 122mm gun and set it up!
122ミリ砲の搬入　及び設置作業にかかれ
Okay!
了解
Ms. Hekmatyar, um, where is the chief doctor?
ヘクマティアルさん
あの　医師長は
He got shot and kidnapped.
撃たれて拐われました
I-I'm terribly sorry.
も…申しわけありませんでした
何を謝るんです
Why are you apologizing?
Baldra and I are the abnormalities here.
この場で異常なのは
バルドラと私なのに
はい　ヘルメット
Here's your helmet!
There will be some rough
turbulence after takeoff.
離陸後かなり揺れますから
Attack once they take off!
離陸直後から仕掛けろ
Shoot them down before they
escape into the clouds. Got that?!
雲ん中に逃げられる前にぶっち殺せ
いいな
You know what will happen
if you fail, don't you? Well?!
殺り損なったらどうなるか分かってんだろなあ
You're just like a little kid.
まるで幼稚園児だ
I can't fathom why anyone would follow you.
貴様に人がついて来るのが理解できん
You may be injured, but you've
still got some life left in you.
弱ってるけどまだまだ平気そうだな
You're going to make a video
letter asking the world to save you
部下が来ったら
「助けてください」って全世界に向けてビデオレターしてよ
after my subordinates get here.
After that, you're dead!
その後　死ね
You're a moron!
バカめ
Let's go!
行っくぞー
テイクオフ
Take off and turn on both IR jammers!
同時に赤外線ジャマーダブルオン
ど畜生が　マジで撃ってきやがったぜ
Damn it! They're seriously firing at us!
That was close!
危ね
Hey, man. That's why
I said flying with Koko is--
オイオイ　だからココと飛ぶと
This isn't Koko's fault, Lehm!
ココに非はありませんよ　レーム
Anti-aircraft guns!
対空砲
They have a powerful infrared jammer!
強力な赤外線ジャマーだ
I can't lock on!
照準が外れる
Connect me with the Missile
Unit 2 in the southwest!
南西に飛んでる第二ミサイル隊につなげ
Chief Pilot, go up! Go up!
機長　もっと高度高度
--Roger.
--Warning! Warning! Incoming missiles!
了解
ミサイルアラート
--That's the missile alert!
--Warning! Warning! Incoming missiles!
Fire the flares!
フレア発射
This is a first!
こんなの初めて
Re-Reload!
じ…次弾を
Don't let them fire, Mao.
撃たせるな　マオ
一万二百六十フィート
We're at 10,260 feet.
Maintaining speed and altitude.
速度　高度維持
You got it.
当然です
Cover your ears!
耳を塞いで口を開けろ
Open your mouths!
Three! Two! One!
three
two
one
The Flechette round made a direct hit!
フレシェット弾　命中
I'll load the next round.
次弾装填します
Sweet!
ヨッシャー
Good thing it hit.
中るもんだな
I only said that to ease tensions.
場を和ませようと言ってみたんだけど
Well done, Mao.
You haven't lost your touch.
よくやった　マオ
錆びてないなあ
6,000 iron darts just rained down on them.
六千本の鉄の矢が降り注いだ
None of those guys can move now,
but don't let your guard down.
動ける者はいまい
だが　警戒は怠るな
Hey, Schokolade! Why on earth
are you soldering in my room?
オイ　ショコラーデ
何で俺の部屋で半田づけしてんだ　オメーはよ
It flipping stinks!
くせーだろか
Instead of whining, take me out to eat.
そんな事より　ご飯おごってくださいよ
Yeah, hello?
あーいーよ　もしもし
Scarecrow, it's me.
スケアクロウ　私だけど
Hekmatyar?! How'd you get my number?!
ヘクマティアル
何で俺の番号
Koko?!
ココちゃん
It was her doing!
こいつか
Listen, I don't have much time.
I'll hang up if you're a pain.
聞け　時間がない
回りくどいと切るぞ
I'm currently in the Balkans' airspace.
今バルカンの上空にいるんだが
I found Dragan.
ドラゴンを見つけた
Say what?!
何　に
Baldra...? The scum worth
5 million dollars on the rewards program?
バルドラって
報奨金プログラム五百万ドルの
Great jo--no, no, you didn't do anything great.
でかし　いやいや　でかしてね
Where is Baldra?
バルカンのどこにいやがる
That's where the info starts.
そこからは情報だ
I'm willing to sell that info and
the honor of apprehending him.
奴を逮捕する名誉と共に売ってあげよ
I want 5 million dollars.
500万ドルだ
Five mill--like hell!
500って　フザケンナ
I don't have a single dollar
to give to a villain like you!
そもそもテメエら悪党に払う金は1ドルもねえ
Really? Too bad.
そっか　残念だ
You're quite a foolish man.
愚かな男だ
She hung up. What a way
to end the conversation!
切りやがった
なんつー捨てぜりふだ
Hi?
はい
Schokolade, I found Dragan in the Balkans.
ショコラーデ
バルカンでドラゴンを見つけたんだ
I'll make it easy for you to apprehend him.
手軽に逮捕できるようにしてあげる
Care to buy this info for 5 million dollars?
このネタ　500万ドルで買わない
Sold!
買うっす
What?! You--!
Man, that was truly a close call.
いや　正に危機一髪
They could have shot us down in one
try if they used the missiles I sold them.
私が売ったミサイルだったら
一発で撃墜されてるところだったね
正に
For sure.
I can't believe you're laughing.
I can't believe it!
よく笑ってられんね
Ms. Hekmatyar, thank you for dropping
us off so close to the refugee camp.
ヘクマティアルさん
難民キャンプのこんな近くまで我々を運んでくださって
ありがとうございました
We will transfer the remaining
fees to your account.
残りの料金は必ず貴方の口座に送ります
Well, we shall be taking our leave now.
それでは　我々はこの辺で
Not yet. Our job here isn't done yet.
まだです
私の仕事はまだ終わっていない
Could you give us some
more time, Ms. Messner?
もう少し時間をいただきます　メスナーさん
Our contract said we were
to bring all ten of you here.
契約は貴方がた十人をここまでお連れすること
We're one short. The order is incomplete.
一人足りない　欠品です
I swear we will get him back.
必ず取り返します
Okay!
はい
So HQ is closely tracing
Baldra's whereabouts via satellite.
っで
バルドラの行方は本部が衛星でバッチリ追跡しているわけだ
Right. We've been actively tracing
him nonstop since the Planina Airport.
ですね
プラニナ空港から今に至るまでつつがなく
Couldn't you make that
sound a little less annoying?
そのムカつく受け答えなんとかならない
Well, I figured this out partway through,
ま　途中から気づいたんだけど
but isn't this whole transaction
part of some scenario Floyd wrote up?
今回の件は全て
フロイドさんの書いたシナリオ　かな
I see you're still estranged to your own father.
相変わらず　実の父御に余所余所しいですね
At any rate, I must tip
my hat to your great wit.
兎にも角にも　ココさんの機転
頭が下がります
It looks like we are going to
get the best results possible.
最高の結果になりそうです
Floyd Hekmatyar's goal was to make
フロイド·ヘクマティアルの目的は医師団の上
the doctor's group and
the CIA feel indebted to him.
そしてCIAの上に恩を売ること
The money received from Baldra's
reward program is yours, Koko.
「バルドラ」の報奨金プログラムはココさんの物です
Scarecrow has just asked for
the U.S. Marines to mobilize.
たった今
スケアクロウが米海兵隊に出動要請をしたとのことです
This is our special ops' last spurt.
特殊作戦グループ
ラストスパートですね　それでは
Take care.
Lehm!
レーム
Yep!
はいよ
It's hunting time.
狩りの時間だよ
Who should I take with me?
誰を連れて行くかね
Wilee, let's use 122mm rounds!
ワイリ　122ミリ砲の弾を使おう
Mao, gather the rounds up.
マオ　弾集めろ
We're commencing the operation.
任務開始だぜ
Those who kill too many
turn into dragons one day.
人を殺し過ぎた人間は
ある日ドラゴンに変わるんだ
Monsters who tread on the ground with
money and soar through the skies with power.
金で地を踏みしめ 権力で空を飛ぶ怪物
As their acts of violence grow worse,
暴力はますます強くなり
they lose their grasp on human speech.
人の言葉なんて通じなくなっていく
People cannot allow
dragons to exist in our world,
人はこの世にドラゴンがいることを許せない
even though they are
monsters of our own creation.
自分たちが生んだ怪物だというのに
Killing a dragon is the ultimate honor.
ドラゴン殺しは最高の名誉
You've gone too far, Baldra.
はしゃぎ過ぎたんだよ　バルドラ
Damn, this hurts!
ッキショゥ　痛ぇ
Curse those wretches...
あの野郎ども
Freaking doctor! Don't think
you'll live to see morning!
医者テメエ　朝まで生きてられると思うなよ
I chose this party without
putting much thought to it,
おお　何の気なしにこの面子にしてみたけど
but the three of us always
go on cleanup duty, don't we?
「後片付け」っつーと昔からこの三人だな
Oh, yeah. Now that you mention it...
いやいや　そう言えば
Clear!
クリア
Wilee's skills with explosives are scary!
ワイリの爆破テク怖いっす
He killed most of them off.
ほぼ全滅だ
That's because they were hit from
below with a 122mm Flechette round.
122ミリフレシェット砲弾を真下から食らわせたかな
It was a landmine.
地雷だぜ
What's that?
何だ
Wh-What's going on?
な…何
鉄の矢
Iron darts?
A Flechette!
フレシェット
We got the doc and Baldra.
お医者さんとバルドラをゲットしたぜ
How's the chief doc holding up? He's just fine.
医師長の様子
ピンピンしてるけど
He isn't the type to die from a bullet wound.
拳銃の弾で死ぬガタイじゃないもんな
We've secured the chief doctor.
医師長を保護しました
Thank you!
ありがとう
Thank you so much, Miss Hekmatyar!
ありがとうございます
ミス·ヘクマティアル
We appreciate it!
感謝します
Thank you for rescuing
Dr. Riviere, Ms. Hekmatyar.
リビエールを救ってくださってありがとう　ヘクマティアルさん
But your power is amazing. Terrifyingly so.
でも
すごい力です
恐ろしくなるほどに
Listening to what you said,
I couldn't help but wonder...
私先の話聞いて思ったんですけど
Are you also a dragon?
貴方も　ドラゴンなのでは
Oh, uh, I don't mean a bad
one like Baldra! I meant--
あ　その
バルドラみたいな悪いのではなくて　その
What a riot! Maggie, you're hilarious.
ツボった
面白い人だマギー
I-I'm sorry...
す…すみません
What's going on?
Did Maggie say something weird again?
何だ何だ
マギーがまた変なこと言ったか
I like the sound of being a dragon.
いいですね　ドラゴン
Maybe then I could soar across
the sky a wee bit more peacefully.
もう少し静かに空を飛べるようになるかもしれない
All done?
終わり
There's one thing left.
後一つ残っている
Hekmatyar!
ヘクマティアル
Oh, so you're the one
calling me now, Scarecrow?
あら　結局アンタからのコールか　スケアクロウ
I take it you found my price acceptable.
納得のお値段だったということですかな
I'll buy it... for 5 million dollars!
買う　500万ドルだ
Thank you for your business.
お買い上げありがとうございます
I just sent you the coordinates of the point.
たった今ポイントの座標をそちらに転送した
Congratulations. Tomorrow this is
going to be the top news story worldwide.
おめでとう
明日の世界中のトップニュースはこのネタだ　アデュー
Adieu!
The villain! Someday I'm going to lock her up!
悪党が
いつかブタ箱にぶち込んでやる
Hey, bring up the location!
オイ　ポイントの画像を
出るっすよ
Coming right up.
Wow! Koko can be brutal!
わあ　ココちゃんやること可愛っす
So this is what she meant
when she said she'd make it easy.
「手軽に逮捕できるよう」ってこういうことか
I'll kill you!
You're so dead, Koko Hekmatyar!
ぶッ殺す
ぶっ殺してやる　ココ·ヘクマティアル
See you around, Jonah! Koko!
またね
ヨナ　ココさん
There's a bunch of weird
doctors out there, eh, Jonah?
なんか医者って変な人多いんだね　ヨナ
Uh-huh.
うん
I like how one called me a dragon.
私のことドラゴンだってのが気に入っちゃたよ
Hey, Jonah? What noise do dragons make?
ね　ヨナ　ドラゴンはどう吠える
"Grah," I think.
「グオオオン」だと思う
Graaah! Graaaah!
グオオオン
光横たえる海神
光怪陸離的海底龍神
Hikari yokotaeru wadatsumi
創痕の間に揺らめく過ち
累累創痕之間搖曳著縷縷罪孽
Soukon no ma ni yurameku ayamachi
浮上して息を継ぎ
浮出水面 吸清吐濁
Fujou shite iki wo tsugi
溶かされ混じるだけの憎愛を手にした
愛與恨 如漆似膠 如影隨形
Tokasare majiru dake no zouai wo te ni shita
矛盾孕む
矛盾誕生
Mujun haramu
この世界ごと 覆い尽くしてる策動の音に傾く夢
冥冥的夢中 世界漸漸傾浸於欺言詭語之中
Kono sekai goto
Ooitsukushiteru sakudou no ne ni katamuku yume
脚は　もう無い
足膝 已沒入虛無
Ashi wa mou nai
水壁を貫く鼓動
透過水壁 傳來陣陣鼓動..
Suiheki wo tsuranuku kodou
惡魔島字幕組(bbs.emland.net)
諸神字幕組(kamigami.org)
Her name is Koko.
She is loco.
I said, "Oh no!"
Her name is Koko.
She is loco.
本字幕由   惡魔島字幕組   &   諸神字幕組   聯合制作
(bbs.emland.net)    (kamigami.org)
日聽 貓日和        日聽 框框
翻譯 TL舊民        校對 YAYA
後期 aoi         時軸 ZZZ
僅供交流學習之用 禁止用於商業用途
諸神字幕組
惡魔島字幕組
I said, "Oh no!"